<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Uncreative IT blog title</title>
    <description>My basic site, created using Jekyll and hosted on Github pages. I hope to add to it soon.
</description>
    <link>http://hgrover.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://hgrover.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 11:48:38 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 11:48:38 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Website</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been wanting to set up some sort of professional website for a while now, and have been unsure of the best way to do it. I have considered paying for a VPS and hosting Wordpress, but have had trouble bringing myself to do so because I figured there would be some better option.  Today I happened to stumble across &lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.github.com&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;, which lets you host a website from your Github respository.  It also lets you set it up at your custom domain name, which was something I wanted.  As such, I decided to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That brought me to the question of how write the website. I’m pretty sure that it only accepts static files, so that rules out anything like Wordpress.  Instead, I went with the option that Github suggests–&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;.  Jekyll is a Ruby site generator that takes text marked down in a number of ways (their own syntax, text, HTML, etc) and spits out a static site.  I’m not sure if I’ll stick with it or find some problem and switch to another option later, but I’d definitely like to give it a shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal for this site is to have a place to store information about my task of learning about IT.  I hope to write posts covering problems I have had (including some that I’ll hopefully solve), and to have a place to host my résumé and generally create a centralized web presence for myself.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 07:45:16 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://hgrover.com/jekyll/site/2015/03/23/newblog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hgrover.com/jekyll/site/2015/03/23/newblog.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>site</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Tom&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &amp;#39;Hi, Tom&amp;#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll-help&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s dedicated Help repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 07:13:16 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://hgrover.com/jekyll/update/2015/03/23/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hgrover.com/jekyll/update/2015/03/23/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
